7079 NE Ronler Way 97124 Hillsboro OR, USA

Mobile: +1 (503) 724 6684

Email: dmitrii.kuvaiskii@gmail.com Homepage: https://dimakuv.github.io/ GitHub: https://github.com/dimakuv

Research Interests

My research interests lie in the field of dependability in software systems, with a particular focus on fault tolerance and security. Within these fields, I investigate the applicability of modern hardware extensions to increase reliability of real-world applications while imposing low overheads. My current research at Intel Labs concentrates on Intel SGX and future security extensions.

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science (Dec 2013 - Jan 2018)

TU Dresden, Germany

Thesis: Hardware-Assisted Dependable Systems, **Summa cum laude** Advisors: Prof. Dr. Christof Fetzer and Prof. Dr. Pramod Bhatotia

M.Sc. in Computer Science (Oct 2011 - Nov 2013)

TU Dresden, Germany

Diplom in Electrical Engineering (Sep 2004 - Jul 2010)

Bauman University, Moscow, Russia

Employment

Intel Labs, Hillsboro, OR, USA, May 2018 - present

Datacenter Security Research Scientist

Responsibilities: hardware/software co-design of security solutions.

Intel Labs, Hillsboro, OR, USA, July 2017 - Sep 2017

Datacenter Security Intern

Responsibilities: developing applications with Intel SGX (C/C++).

Auriga Inc, Moscow, Russia, Sep 2010 - Aug 2011

Certification engineer, Software developer

Responsibilities:

- documenting and testing code of the PikeOS embedded operating system (C);
- writing medical special-purpose programs (C++ and C#).

Diasoft, Moscow, Russia, Sep 2007 - Aug 2010

Software developer

Responsibilities: programming insurance subsystems using Transact SQL and Delphi.

Honors and Awards

Summa cum laude for PhD thesis, 2018

Best paper award at EuroSys'17

Carter Award (best student paper) at DSN'15

Best paper award at SRDS'14

Erasmus Mundus Action 2 MULTIC scholarship, 2011-2013

Ph.D. Dissertation

Topic: Hardware-Assisted Dependable Systems

Supervisors: Prof. Dr. Christof Fetzer and Prof. Dr. Pramod Bhatotia

In the context of my Ph.D. dissertation, I investigated and built systems to increase software dependability leveraging recent sets of extensions in Intel processors, with the focus on software-based fault tolerance and security for legacy C/C++ programs.

Research projects:

Detailed evaluation of Intel MPX and discussion of its applicability in comparison to other bounds-checking approaches [ACM SIGMETRICS'18];

SGXBounds: LLVM-based bounds checker to detect and tolerate security bugs in multithreaded legacy C/C++ programs inside Intel SGX enclaves [EuroSys'17];

Elzar: LLVM compiler pass to detect and mask transient CPU faults in multithreaded legacy C/C++ programs using Intel AVX [**DSN'16**] [code];

HAFT: LLVM compiler pass to detect and tolerate transient CPU faults in multithreaded legacy C/C++ programs using Intel TSX [EuroSys'16] [code];

Δ-*Encoding*: Source-to-source compiler to detect transient and permanent CPU faults in legacy C programs utilizing unused IPC resources of modern CPUs [**DSN'15**].

Publications

Conference publications:

Intel MPX Explained

Oleksii Oleksenko, Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Pramod Bhatotia, Pascal Felber, and Christof Fetzer

ACM SIGMETRICS 2018.

Fex: A software systems evaluator

Oleksii Oleksenko, Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Pramod Bhatotia, and Christof Fetzer

DSN 2017.

SGXBounds: Memory Safety for Shielded Execution

Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Oleksii Oleksenko, Sergei Arnautov, Bohdan Trach, Pramod Bhatotia, Pascal Felber, and Christof Fetzer

EuroSys 2017. Best paper award.

Elzar: Triple Modular Redundancy using Intel Advanced Vector Extensions

Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Oleksii Oleksenko, Pramod Bhatotia, Pascal Felber, and Christof Fetzer

DSN 2016.

HAFT: Hardware-Assisted Fault Tolerance

Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Rasha Faqeh, Pramod Bhatotia, Pascal Felber, and Christof Fetzer **EuroSys 2016**.

Δ-Encoding: Practical Encoded Processing

Dmitrii Kuvaiskii and Christof Fetzer

DSN 2015. Carter Award (best student paper).

Needles in the Haystack—Tackling Bit Flips in Lightweight Compressed Data *Till Kolditz, Dirk Habich, Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Wolfgang Lehner, and Christof Fetzer* **DATA 2015**.

HardPaxos: Replication hardened against hardware errors *Diogo Behrens, Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, and Christof Fetzer* **SRDS 2014**. Best paper award.

Other Publications:

Snort Intrusion Detection System with Intel Software Guard Extension (Intel SGX) *Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Somnath Chakrabarti, and Mona Vij* **ArXiv.org 2018**.

Open Source Projects

Intel MPX Explained https://intel-mpx.github.io

SGXBounds

https://github.com/tudinfse/sgxbounds

Elzar

https://github.com/tudinfse/elzar

HAFT

https://github.com/tudinfse/haft

SEC-IDS aka Snort-SGX

https://github.com/cloud-security-research/sgx-ids

Graphene-SGX (contributor)

https://github.com/oscarlab/graphene

Talks

ACM EuroSys'17, Belgrade, April 2017

SGXBounds: Memory Safety for Shielded Execution

ACM EuroSys'16, London, April 2016 HAFT: Hardware-Assisted Fault Tolerance

IEEE DSN'16, Toulouse, June 2016

Elzar: Triple Modular Redundancy using Intel Advanced Vector Extensions

IEEE DSN'15, Rio de Janeiro, June 2015

Δ-Encoding: Practical Encoded Processing

Teaching experience

Teaching assistant: Distributed Systems Engineering courses, TU Dresden, Dec 2013 - Jan 2018.

- Concurrent and Distributed Systems lab, Summer Semesters 2014 2016
- Principles of Dependable Systems exercises, Winter Semesters 2014 2018
- Software Fault Tolerance exercises, Summer Semesters 2014 2018

Professional activities

Shadow PC member: EuroSys 2016.

Skills

Languages: C, C++, Assembly (expert), Unix shell, Python, R (competent);

Frameworks: LLVM, gdb, Intel Pin, Intel SDE;

Technologies: Intel SSE/AVX, Intel TSX, Intel MPX, Intel SGX.

References

Prof. Dr. Christof Fetzer

TU Dresden, Germany

Email: christof.fetzer@tu-dresden.de

Prof. Dr. Pramod Bhatotia

University of Edinburgh, UK

Email: pramod.bhatotia@ed.ac.uk

Prof. Dr. Pascal Felber

University of Neuchatel

Email: pascal.felber@unine.ch

Mona Vij

Intel Labs, USA

Email: mona.vij@intel.com